So I would now like
to consider systems
in which the total momentum
of the system is zero.
And show that L, the
angular momentum,
is independent of the
choice of point A. So let's
consider this.
Let's draw a picture
here and let's
make our system a bunch of
discrete particles, particle
one particle two.
And let's call this
the j-th particle.
And let's just choose
a point A right here,
and let's choose a
point B right there.
And I'll show that L
for this system about A
is going to be equal to
L of the system about B.
In order to make an
angular momentum diagram
we have the momentum
Pj of this particle.
And likewise, for all
the other particles.
And I'll draw a
vector R A,j Likewise,
for B I'll draw
the vector R B,j.
And I'm also going to
draw a vector from B
to A. I'll make that capital.
This vector is a constant
because the points A
and B, here, A and
B are fixed points.
Now let's calculate
the angular momentum
about A for the system.
It's the sum of j goes from 1 to
n of the vector R A,j cross Pj.
And I can use the angular
momentum of the system about B
is j goes from 1 to
n of R B,j cross Pj.
Now I'll use the
vector triangle,
that the vector from B to j
is equal to the vector from B
to A plus the
vector from A to j.
So we have that R B,j is equal
to the vector from B to A plus
the vector from A to j.
And I'll substitute that into
our expression for the angular
moment about B. So the angular
momentum about B is the sum j
goes from 1 to n of R
B,A plus R A,j cross Pj.
Now the vector
product distributes
over vector addition.
So this is two sums.
So let's write them both out.
J goes from 1 to n of R B,A
cross Pj plus the sum j goes
from 1 to n of R A,j cross Pj.
Now already you're seeing
that this term is the angular
momentum of the system
about A. This term
is the interesting one.
R P,A is a constant vector.
No matter which
particle I choose,
one, two, the j-th particle,
this vector is always the same.
So I can pull it out of the sum
and I get R B,A cross product
the sum of j goes
from 1 to and of Pj.
Now we've already
recognized this term
as the angular momentum
of the system about A.
And this is just the total
momentum of the system.
So we have equal to R B,A
cross the total momentum
of the system plus the angular
momentum of the system about A.
And that's the angular
momentum of the system about B.
So this is our general result
about how angular momentum
differ between two points.
But now, if P system equals to
zero, the first term is zero,
then L of the system
about B is equal to the L
of the system about A.
We've proved our proposition
that if the total
momentum of the system
is zero then the
angular momentum doesn't
depend on the point we choose.
Now what's interesting here is
that the reference frame moving
with the center of
mass, by definition,
has P in that frame,
let's call it the system.
And this is the cm frame
is zero by definition.
So this is one more reason why
the center of mass reference
frame is an important
reference frame.
Because in the center
of mass reference frame,
the total momentum, by
definition, is zero.
And therefore, the
angular momentum
is independent of
any point that you
choose in that reference frame.
And so we can say
that the system, when
we talk about a system's
angular momentum,
we're referring to the
angular momentum in the center
of mass reference frame.